<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Daniel Quan]]></title>
  <link href="http://djquan.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://djquan.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-11T16:30:18-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://djquan.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Daniel Quan]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[djquan@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Objective C]]></title>
    <link href="http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/06/11/objective-c/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-11T12:57:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/06/11/objective-c</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been struggling a little bit with getting into Objective C.  Ruby is really a fun language to program in, and that was one of the goals it was designed for.  I&rsquo;m really appreciating that more as I dive a little into Objective C.  Granted, it is only through the Code School tutorial, so there may be other best practices and ways to do it that actually make it better.  Take for example functions.  This is an example from the tutorial:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>TalkingiPhone.h (header)</span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='objc'><span class='line'><span class="k">@interface</span> <span class="nc">TalkingiPhone</span> : <span class="nc">NSObject</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">@property</span> <span class="n">NSString</span> <span class="o">*</span><span class="n">phoneName</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">@property</span> <span class="n">NSString</span> <span class="o">*</span><span class="n">modelNumber</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">-</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">NSString</span> <span class="o">*</span><span class="p">)</span><span class="nf">speak:</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">NSString</span> <span class="o">*</span><span class="p">)</span><span class="nv">greeting</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">@end</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>




<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>TalkingiPhone.m (implementation)</span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='objc'><span class='line'><span class="cp">#import &quot;TalkingiPhone.h&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">@implementation</span> <span class="nc">TalkingiPhone</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">-</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">NSString</span> <span class="o">*</span><span class="p">)</span><span class="nf">speak:</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">NSString</span> <span class="o">*</span><span class="p">)</span><span class="nv">greeting</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">NSString</span> <span class="o">*</span><span class="n">message</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="p">[</span><span class="n">NSString</span> <span class="nl">stringWithFormat:</span><span class="s">@&quot;%@ says %@&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">self</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">phoneName</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">greeting</span><span class="p">];</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="n">message</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">@end</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>This just seems really verbose and not intuitive. I mean, the whole thing in ruby could be as simple as:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>talkingiPhone.rb</span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="k">class</span> <span class="nc">TalkingiPhone</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">initialize</span> <span class="nb">name</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="vi">@phoneName</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nb">name</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">end</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">speak</span> <span class="n">greeting</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">message</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s2">&quot;</span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="vi">@phoneName</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2"> says </span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="n">greeting</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2">&quot;</span> <span class="c1"># &quot;message = &quot; is optional, but I kept it in.</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">end</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">end</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>That&rsquo;s much more simple, right? No confusing syntax&hellip;no need for explicit variable declarations with type.</p>

<p>Of course the entire code example is trivial in its functionality; but I&rsquo;m sure the point is even more valid the more complex the program will get.</p>

<p>Objective C is still a valuable language to be familiar with, and I fully intend to keep pushing forward on it. I do want to play around with Ruby Motion, but you still need to know your way around objective c for it(since you can use the same APIs and libraries).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vim and Me]]></title>
    <link href="http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/06/08/vim-and-me/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-08T15:31:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/06/08/vim-and-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Introduction</strong></p>

<p>vim is a text editor, but it is so much more too.  This post will go over why vim works <em>for me</em> and my setup, including plugins.</p>

<p>This post will be similar to my <a href="http://quan.io/blog/2013/05/14/tmux/">post on tmux</a>, with an emphasis on the plugins I use and how they fit into my workflow.  I am a beginner;  I still have a tremendous amount of learning about vim, <em>and this post is for fellow beginners out there.</em></p>

<p>This is also not a &ldquo;vim is better than sublime/emacs/textmate/eclipse/rubymine&rdquo; post.  This is just me laying out some thoughts on my experience with vim and my setup.</p>

<p>This is not a guide on how to use vim.  Check out some of the links at the bottom for some good resources.  The <em>best</em> resource on vim (that I have found) is Practical Vim by Drew Neil.</p>

<p>Moreover, this is also serving as a way to downsize my vimrc file by justifying everything in it.</p>

<p>My recommendation is, no matter what editor you use, think about how to improve your workflow and become more efficient.  Is there a way you can do what you want with less keystrokes?  Do you really need to reach for the mouse?  What plugins are your favorite, and are you using them in the best way?  How can you make your editor leaner?</p>

<p><img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/6565481/vim.png" alt="vim" /></p>

<p><strong>Does a beginner really need to use vim?</strong></p>

<p>No, of course not.  I came to vim only after I felt comfortable with ruby, looking to improve my workflow. My advice: make sure you have that some comfort with whatever language(s) you chose before experimenting with vim.</p>

<p>That said, learning vim early can do a few good things.  So you made a mistake and didn&rsquo;t press a or i to enter insert mode to begin typing.  Well, you can retype it again and have the added bonus of repetition in learning the basics.  You also get the baby-steps and issues of learning vim out of the way, so that when you <em>need</em> to be typing fast with few mistakes, you can.  To put it another way, make your mistakes now in both vim and #{whatever programming language you are learning} so that you won&rsquo;t make them later.</p>

<p><strong>Why should I even bother?</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Efficiency &ndash; Modal editing, despite taking a while to get a hang of, can lead to improving efficiency. The mouse, while typing, is the enemy.  The time it takes to move between the mouse and keyboard can add up.</li>
<li>The Dot command &ndash; Vim knows what you did last. Actions, like adding text, deleting lines, can be repeated by pressing . on your keyboard.  This is extremely powerful in programming, where often you need to repeat an action.</li>
<li>Text Objects &ndash;  Text objects, when combined with modal editing, are great.  Say I&rsquo;m typing a sentence, and I want to rewrite the entire thing.  I can press cis anywhere in that sentence to delete it all and throw me into insert mode.  They are pretty cool.</li>
<li>Editing text on a server &ndash; If you haven&rsquo;t already, someday soon any beginner will eventually get to the point where he has to edit text on a server. That server will have vim on it. Any investment, even if you chose to edit with something else primarily, in learning vim can pay off when that comes up.</li>
<li>Command line &ndash; Even without tmux, it is easy to use the command line and all of it&rsquo;s power from the editor itself.</li>
<li>Vim + Tmux = Amazingness</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Plugins</strong> (in no particular order)</p>

<p><em><a href="https://github.com/gmarik/vundle">Vundle</a></em>:
Vundle is a plugin manager. Basically, installing a plugin with it involves adding &lsquo;Bundle &ldquo;github/pathofplugin&rdquo;&rsquo; to your vimrc file, and typing :BundleInstall in vim (after reloading your source file).  Use this or Tim Pope&rsquo;s <a href="https://github.com/tpope/vim-pathogen">Pathogen</a> for managing your plugins.  Both are great.</p>

<p><em><a href="https://github.com/kien/ctrlp.vim">Ctrl-P</a></em>:
Ctrl-P is a fuzzy file finder for vim. It is quick and efficient. It&rsquo;s much more efficient than &ldquo;:e filename.rb&rdquo; and is my preferred method of finding files.</p>

<p><em><a href="https://github.com/godlygeek/tabular">Tabularize</a></em>:
Tabular makes it easy to align text based on a target. There is a nice <a href="http://vimcasts.org/episodes/aligning-text-with-tabular-vim/">vimcast</a> that does a great job explaining this. Basically, if I wanted to align text for variable assignment based on an equal sign, I could just type :Tab /=  and all of the equal signs would be aligned in the same column.</p>

<p><em><a href="https://github.com/tpope/vim-unimpaired">Unimpaired</a></em>:
Unimpaired provides handy shortcuts for switching between buffers/args/etc. Instead of pressing &ldquo;:bn&rdquo; to get to the next buffer, unimapired allows you to press [b to get to the next buffer.</p>

<p><em><a href="https://github.com/benmills/vimux">vimux</a></em>:
Allows easy integration with tmux.  Bind a leader combo to open up a new tmux pane and run a command in it.  Amazing.  Also, amazing in conjunction with vim-turbux.</p>

<p><em><a href="https://github.com/jgdavey/vim-turbux">vim-turbux</a></em>:
See above, automates the process of testing in conjunction with tmux.</p>

<p><em><a href="https://github.com/tpope/vim-endwise">vim-endwise</a></em>:
Adds &ldquo;end&rdquo; wherever it needs be automatically.  class, def, if, it should do; can handle them all and more.</p>

<p><em><a href="https://github.com/townk/vim-autoclose">vim-autoclose</a></em>:
Autocloses parenthesis, brackets, quotes, single quotes, backticks, etc.  Helpful.</p>

<p><em><a href="https://github.com/jeffkreeftmeijer/vim-numbertoggle">vim-numbertoggle</a></em>:
This one has grown on me.  I like relative number for ease of navigating.  Relative number lets me not have to count as much.  I don&rsquo;t need relative number on all the time, and numbertoggle switches between them when I go into insert mode.</p>

<p><em><a href="http://github.com/mattn/gist-vim">gist-vim</a></em>:
This one I don&rsquo;t use enough to have anything memorized.  But it is there, and allows easy code sharing when I need it.</p>

<p><em><a href="https://github.com/tpope/vim-fugitive">vim-fugitive</a></em>:
An amazing plugin; if you are a heavy git user, this alone might be enough to make you switch to vim. <a href="http://vimcasts.org/episodes/fugitive-vim---a-complement-to-command-line-git/">Vimcasts</a> has a nice set of tutorials on using fugitive.  The short of it is: vim-fugitive gives you the history(through git) on changes, files, and commits. Typing :Gdiff opens up a split pane with a line by line colored comparison of changes I have made to a file.</p>

<p><em><a href="https://github.com/epmatsw/ag.vim">ag</a></em>:
The vim plugin for integrating the silver searcher.  The Silver Searcher is a replacement for Ack, which is often used instead of grep.  This plugin gives you a nice popup menu for ag searches by typing :Ag &ldquo;searchterm&rdquo;<CR></p>

<p><em><a href="https://github.com/tpope/vim-rails">vim-rails</a></em>:
This plugin is obviously only good for those rails developers out there.  Enhanced syntax highlighting is nice, but just the tip.  Vim-rails has ways of easily and intelligently navigating the directory ~ it knows your controllers, your models, and your views.  There are more features, but I&rsquo;m still learning them.</p>

<p><em><a href="https://github.com/scrooloose/syntastic">vim-syntastic</a></em>:
Points out syntax errors.  On write(:w), it&rsquo;ll check and throw arrows in the margin of lines it thinks there&rsquo;s issues with.  These issues could be a number of things that it thinks is wrong.</p>

<p><em><a href="https://github.com/tpope/vim-surround">vim-surround</a></em>:
Another fantastic plugin by Tim Pope.  Say I wanted to change a string declaration from a = &ldquo;hello&rdquo; to a = &lsquo;hello&rsquo;.   I just place my cursor on any letter in hello and type cs&#8221;&lsquo; and it changes it automatically. Especially helpful with changing HTML tags since you can replace things with valid html. It can also add (instead of just changing) with ys[textobject][whatever you want to add].</p>

<p><em><a href="https://github.com/mattn/zencoding-vim">zencoding</a></em>:
Zencoding/Emmet is a way of expanding short bits of code into longform html. Definitely check out the video here, <a href="http://docs.emmet.io/">http://docs.emmet.io/</a> .  It&rsquo;s an extremely efficient way of writing html.</p>

<p>I probably still need a good snippet tool.  I&rsquo;m looking at ultisnip or snipmate; I haven&rsquo;t really felt the need to have one <em>yet</em>.  Vim-Autoclose and endwise help a lot already.  Zencoding handles much of my html needs.</p>

<p><strong> Some helpful .vimrc lines </strong></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m pretty sure I got all of these from Drew Neil.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='vim'><span class='line'><span class="c">&quot; Easy expansion of filepath. Type %% in command mode and it puts your current directory</span>
</span><span class='line'>cnoremap <span class="p">&lt;</span>expr<span class="p">&gt;</span> %% getcmdtype<span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">==</span> <span class="s1">&#39;:&#39;</span> ? expand<span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;%:h&#39;</span><span class="p">)</span>.<span class="s1">&#39;/&#39;</span> : <span class="s1">&#39;%%&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">&quot;Reloads source file on save</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">if</span> has<span class="p">(</span><span class="s2">&quot;autocmd&quot;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>  autocmd bufwritepost .vimrc source $MYVIMRC
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">endif</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">&quot;Leader - v to open sourcefile</span>
</span><span class='line'>nmap <span class="p">&lt;</span>Leader<span class="p">&gt;</span><span class="k">v</span> :<span class="k">vsp</span> $MYVIMRC<span class="p">&lt;</span>CR<span class="p">&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">&quot; adds dot command to visual mode </span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nb">vnoremap</span> . :norm.<span class="p">&lt;</span>CR<span class="p">&gt;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p><strong>Negatives</strong></p>

<p>There is no getting around it:  Vim has a learning curve.  However, it may not be as steep as you think.  It may take a few days for the basic ideas of normal/insert/visual/etc modes to click.  Navigating may be tricky at first.  You may find yourself wishing that you had a mouse on many occasions.  But it passes, and you gain efficiency eventually.</p>

<p>Vim requires out of the box work to get it configured. This is only a negative in the short-term.  In the long term, you have a better understanding of the features in your text editor because you worked to get them there.  I also feel that the small decisions I make in setting it up add up to really make the vim I work on unique and &lsquo;mine.&rsquo;</p>

<p>I can&rsquo;t remember where I heard it from(I think it was the peepcode screencast on vim), but someone said that your .vimrc file is something you can grow old with. Someone also said that if you don&rsquo;t think your .vimrc is the best there is, you need to work on it more.</p>

<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>

<p>Vim is a highly customizable text editor.  Getting it set up is an extremely personal ordeal, and I would recommend against using packages that advertise to be the ultimate vim distribution.  One of the great things about vim is that at the end of the day, you are left with an editor that is <em>yours</em>.  Get to know your plugins.  Get to know every setting you have and what it does.  This will help you get the most out of it.</p>

<p>If I haven&rsquo;t convinced you to try vim, I hope I have convinced you to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Love what editor you do use (we spend enough time on them that this is crucial)</li>
<li>Think of ways you can improve it</li>
<li>Think of ways you can be more efficient</li>
</ul>


<p>There are probably countless amazing plugins I haven&rsquo;t mentioned.  My recommendation: don&rsquo;t get caught up in all the &ldquo;what plugin&rdquo; should I use for x until a little later.  Learn the vim basics, and then go plugin-crazy.  Vim is awesome without plugins; plugins just make it that much more amazing.</p>

<p><strong>Resources</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://pragprog.com/book/dnvim/practical-vim">Practical Vim</a> ($)</li>
<li><a href="http://mislav.uniqpath.com/2011/12/vim-revisited/">Vim Revisted</a></li>
<li><a href="http://vimcasts.org">Vimcasts</a></li>
<li><a href="http://vimcasts.org/classes/core-vim">Vim Masterclass</a> ($$)</li>
<li><a href="http://vim-adventures.com/">Vim Adventures</a></li>
<li><a href="https://learn.thoughtbot.com/products/2-vim-for-rails-developers">Vim for Rails Developers</a>($$)</li>
<li>Vimtutor (Type vimtutor in your shell)</li>
<li>Peep Code has a couple screencasts on vim; I would recommend just watching any of the play by plays (many/most of them use vim).  Ben Orenstein&rsquo;s, in particular, is pretty great on SO many levels.  He also has a <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SkdrYWhh-8s">pretty good talk</a> on developing in vim.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Design]]></title>
    <link href="http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/06/07/update/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-07T14:19:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/06/07/update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve started to dive into some more design resources.</p>

<p>Code School&rsquo;s Journey into Mobile is a pretty good introduction to responsive design. Responsive design is designing your site so that it looks good in varying resolutions and devices.  It is extremely important with the variety of ways people can visit a site. It involves using percentages or ems (relative units in css).  Also, it involves finding &ldquo;break points&rdquo;, resolutions which the site design changes. All in all, it was eye opening at the amount of thought and work that it takes to make a site responsive; especially since tools like Twitter&rsquo;s Bootstrap can hide all the magic of responsive design.</p>

<p>Sass is stylesheet language that compiles into CSS.  It lets you do more with less lines of code.  It&rsquo;s similar to CoffeeScript, in the sense that it 1.) simplifies the syntax and 2.) makes it feel more like a programming language.  For example, the text below is in Sass.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='sass'><span class='line'><span class="nv">$authors</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="n">bob</span> <span class="n">tim</span> <span class="n">sue</span> <span class="n">kate</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nc">.author</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="na">float</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="no">left</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="na">width</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="mi">100</span><span class="kt">%</span> <span class="o">/</span> <span class="nf">length</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">$authors</span><span class="p">)</span>  <span class="c1">// automatically updates if $authors changes</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>$authors is a list, which functions much like an array.  You can iterate through it using each, find the index of a value, and many more commands you&rsquo;d expect from an array.  The example above automatically updates the width of a css selector (.author) to adjust to adding new authors.</p>

<p>Log</p>

<ul>
<li>Thoughtbot &ndash; Completed Test Driven Rails Workshop</li>
<li>Thoughtbot &ndash; Design for Developers Workshop, Principles of Visual Design</li>
<li>Code School &ndash; Assembling Saas, Part I</li>
<li>Code School &ndash; Assembling Sass, Part II</li>
<li>Code School &ndash; Journey into Mobile</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[and back]]></title>
    <link href="http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/06/03/and-back/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-03T16:43:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/06/03/and-back</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back to learning!</p>

<p>I recommend checking out the Ruby Rogues episode on imposter syndrom.  As someone new to programming, it&rsquo;s nice to hear that even the experts can feel like they don&rsquo;t belong or people will realize that they don&rsquo;t know as much as they should.</p>

<p>I attended Spree Conf in DC; and I definitely felt that I didn&rsquo;t belong, and that created a lot of fear and anxiety. I&rsquo;ve been studying for over four months, and I&rsquo;m fairly accomplished in other areas, but it was still terrifying to be that new person in the room.  This RubyRogues episode definitely has helped my outlook, and I&rsquo;m excited to go to my next conference (RubyNation!).</p>

<p>I recently attended a webinar on vim by Drew Neil, the man who wrote <em>Practical Vim</em>.  I definitely recommend attending; it is easily worth the relatively steep price.  I&rsquo;d read (or skim) the book and check out some of his vimcasts beforehand to get the most out of it.  The major focus points were: Macros and text objects, but I also feel more comfortable just dealing with registers, buffers, and args.</p>

<p>vim helpful tip for your .vimrc.  This lets you use the dot command in visual mode. Great for applying the last change on many lines.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='vim'><span class='line'><span class="c">&quot; adds dot command to visual mode &quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nb">vnoremap</span> . :norm.<span class="p">&lt;</span>CR<span class="p">&gt;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Say you wanted to add a semicolon to multiple lines.</p>

<p>A;       ~  Appends a semicolon to the current line</p>

<p>vG       ~  Selects to the last line of the file, could easily be a different selector.</p>

<p>.         ~  Appends a semicolon to every line selected.</p>

<p>No idea why this doesn&rsquo;t work out of the box for vim.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Node.js and more]]></title>
    <link href="http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/05/25/updates/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-25T21:47:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/05/25/updates</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This will probably be my last update for about a week.  I&rsquo;m driving cross country on monday, so I won&rsquo;t have too much time to update the blog.  I do plan on learning more through various audio podcasts during the drive.  Some of them include:</p>

<ul>
<li>The Changelog</li>
<li>RubyRogues</li>
<li>Giant Robots Smashing into Other Giant Robots</li>
<li>Ruby Freelancers</li>
<li>Javascript Jabber</li>
</ul>


<p>Feel free to post suggestions in the comments section. Learning to program is inherently visual and tactile, but there must be some other good audio only resources out there.  It is too bad there aren&rsquo;t many audio versions of technical books.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve written a bit on Thoughtbot&rsquo;s Learn Prime.  This week, they had a pretty awesome &ldquo;Ask Me Anything&rdquo; session with Ben Orenstein. More features like this would definitely make Learn Prime appealing after I have finished all of their workshops.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve signed up for an online <a href="http://vimcasts.org/classes/core-vim">vim seminar</a> on June 3rd that should raise my vim skills to the next level. I&rsquo;ll be sure to post my thoughts on that.</p>

<p>Web development is much more than knowing how to write a Ruby on Rails app.  Learning javascript well is becoming a major priority for me.  Javascript isn&rsquo;t the prettiest language, but a lot of the exciting frameworks (backbone, ember, node, angular) rely on it.</p>

<p>Node.js is a server-side system of responding to events quickly and reliably. I definitely recommend the Code School course on it.  It was one of the more challenging courses, and I learned more because of that.</p>

<p>Log for 5/23 &ndash; 5/25</p>

<ul>
<li>Code School &ndash; Real Time Web with Node.js</li>
<li>Thoughtbot &ndash; Test Driven Rails, Interacting with 3rd Party Services</li>
<li>Code School &ndash; Discover Dev Tools</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[progress]]></title>
    <link href="http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/05/22/progress/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-22T17:47:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/05/22/progress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The RubyNation <a href="http://www.rubynation.org/schedule">Speaker List</a> looks amazing. Sandi Metz, Avdi Grimm, Russ Olsen, Steve Klabnik&hellip;I&rsquo;m definitely excited about it.</p>

<p>CoffeScript is a language that compiles into javascript.  The Code School course on CoffeeScript was a nice introduction to it, and it was also a good refresher on basic javascript.  The course has a lot of examples of translating from javascript and jquery into pure coffeescript, which I found really helpful.</p>

<p>There is a lot <a href="http://wekeroad.com/2012/03/21/coffeescript-or-straight-up-js-i-suck-either-way/">written</a> about the pros and cons of CoffeeScript weighed against pure JavaScript. I do like that CoffeeScript appears to be more similar in syntax to Ruby. I don&rsquo;t look it as a JavaScript vs CoffeeScript choice.  To write well in CoffeeScript, you need to have a firm understanding of basic JavaScript to debug errors and really understand what&rsquo;s going on.</p>

<p>Recently, I&rsquo;ve done a fair amount of coding(and blogging) using vim exclusively, and I&rsquo;ve been thrilled with how it&rsquo;s going.  I&rsquo;ve improved my efficiency by not having to switch windows to perform tests, rake tasks, or any other command line work.  Moreover, being able to work quickly without using the mouse at all is liberating.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m still reading through <a href="http://pragprog.com/book/dnvim/practical-vim">Practical Vim</a>, and it&rsquo;s been a great resource so far. I still need to learn more about registers (vim&rsquo;s tools to copy and paste).  I also still need to find a snippet(ways of expanding text) solution that works well for me.  Still, I can&rsquo;t see myself moving away from vim+tmux anytime soon.</p>

<p>Log for 5/20 &ndash; 5/22</p>

<ul>
<li>Finished the Jumpstart Labs EventManager Tutorial</li>
<li>Thoughtbot &ndash; Test Driven Rails, Writing Unit Tests</li>
<li>Code School &ndash; Anatomy of Backbone.js Part 2</li>
<li>Code School &ndash; CoffeeScript</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Law and Development]]></title>
    <link href="http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/05/19/progress/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-19T18:17:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/05/19/progress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Ruby Rogues episode on <a href="http://rubyrogues.com/105-rr-regular-expressions-with-nell-shamrell/">regular expressions</a> is pretty awesome. Regular expressions are a way to express patterns in a programming language.  Regular expressions are powerful, but can be very intimidating. <a href="http://rubular.com">Rubular</a> is a nice tool to play around with them, and the chapter on regular expressions in <em>The Well Grounded Rubyist</em> provides a great explanation.</p>

<p>I passed the CA bar exam! That being said, landing a job as a web developer is still my number one goal.  Being a lawyer will be just another skill that I bring to the table.  This means that I&rsquo;ll need to find resources to learn about laws and regulations that affect start-ups. Being a web developer that can also handle routine and simple legal issues will help me stand out.  Web Developer / Counsel would be a nice job title.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.lawline.com/">Lawline</a> might be a good resource to learn more. I tried a course on them about negotating SaaS deals which was pretty informative. A general theme of the video was to be explicit about every provision, including confidentiality and ownership. The instructor also stated that the majority of contracts created by tech vendors are pretty horrible because companies tend to reuse old contract and they aren&rsquo;t clear on the intent of the agreement.</p>

<p>Heads up, Code School will be <a href="http://www.codeschool.com/free-weekend?fb_action_ids=10201128707883052&amp;fb_action_types=og.likes&amp;fb_ref=.UZaSvvvXBpk.send&amp;fb_source=aggregation&amp;fb_aggregation_id=288381481237582">free</a> May 25th to May 26th. Code School is a fantastic <em>starting off point</em> for many topics.  Their courses are always well made and designed.</p>

<p>Log for 5/17-5/19</p>

<ul>
<li>Lawline.com &ndash; The Art and Science of Negotiating SaaS(Software as a service) Deals</li>
<li><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T8J0j2xJFgQ">Confident Code</a> talk by Avdi Grimm</li>
<li>Ruby Rogues &ndash; Episode 105, Regular Expressions with Nell Shamrell</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[relative numbers]]></title>
    <link href="http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/05/16/progress/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-16T14:14:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/05/16/progress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the great things about the ruby (and software community in general) is that there are a lot of resources available to learn from.</p>

<p><a href="http://destroyallsoftware.com">Destroy All Software</a> has just made the screencasts available for purchase by season. They weren&rsquo;t available for the past few months while Gary Bernhardt switched pricing models.  I&rsquo;m working through the first season right now and am learning a lot.  It&rsquo;s almost worth it alone to see how fast and efficient he is with vim.</p>

<p>Vim tip: Relative numbers is a <a href="http://forum.thoughtbot.com/t/give-set-relativenumber-a-try/22">winner</a>.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='vim'><span class='line'><span class="k">set</span> <span class="nb">relativenumber</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>I like using the <a href="https://github.com/jeffkreeftmeijer/vim-numbertoggle">numbertoggle</a> plugin. It automatically switches to absolute numbers when I switch to insert mode, and it switches back to relative numbers when I leave.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/05/16/octopress/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-16T13:33:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/05/16/octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, the switch to Octopress seems pretty complete.  Here are just a few of my thoughts on it.</p>

<p>Give octopress a try. It&rsquo;s easy to set up.  It&rsquo;s easy to post content.</p>

<ul>
<li>Octopress makes it incredibly easy to write and publish from the command line.</li>
<li>Everything about an octopress blog will be stored locally.</li>
<li>This gives freedom to switch publishing platforms or web hosts and a local backup of posts(with version control!).</li>
<li>Octopress is made for coders.  Inserting code snippets is incredibly easy.  There are also a large number of plugins to extend functionality.</li>
</ul>


<p>I will miss some aspects of tumblr.</p>

<ul>
<li>Tumblr is an incredible way to make connections and really is social blogging at its best.</li>
<li>Tumblr has apps to make mobile publishing simple.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migration from Tumblr]]></title>
    <link href="http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/05/15/migration-from-tumblr/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-15T15:31:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/05/15/migration-from-tumblr</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I will slowly be making a move from tumblr to octopress.</p>

<p>Octopress is a framework built on Jekyll, a static blog generator.</p>

<p>I think as I get more familiar with it, the switch to octopress will allow me a greater ability to customize the site.
Moreover, octopress (and jekyll) allow me a greater freedom in how I write my posts.</p>

<p>I have been trying for the past few hours on ways of importing my older posts from tumblr.  I&rsquo;ve tried a variety of methods, including <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/docs/migrations/">jekyll-import</a>
but have run into issues.  I&rsquo;ll keep playing around with it though!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[tmux]]></title>
    <link href="http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/05/14/tmux/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-14T15:55:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/05/14/tmux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Intro to tmux</strong></p>


<p>tmux is a terminal multiplexer. &nbsp;At it&#8217;s most basic, it allows you create windows and panes inside a tmux session. &nbsp;Each window and pane is a separate instance of a terminal. &nbsp;</p>


<p>I&#8217;ll try to explain why tmux works <em>for me</em>, and I&#8217;ll finish with links on how to set it up. &nbsp;</p>


<p>This is not aimed to be a guide on setting up tmux, or how to use tmux. &nbsp;It is just an explanation of why it has become essential<em> to me</em>, and why it is worth a try. &nbsp;There are alternatives; iterm2 has it&#8217;s own way of handling panes; there is also screen. &nbsp;I haven&#8217;t tried either, and I&#8217;m not implying that tmux is better than either. &nbsp;</p>


<p><span>Also, I am still a novice; I have a tremendous amount to learn about improving my workflow.</span></p>


<p><a href="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/6565481/tmux.png"><img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/7ca4b1bdf4c5fb7d5ab1d5dfe10cad9a/tumblr_inline_mmt29dEyHR1qz4rgp.png" /></a></p>


<p><strong>Panes, Panes, Panes.</strong></p>


<p>Since I began to code through test-driven-development, I almost always code so that I can see both my test file and the code that it is testing. &nbsp;In sublime, this involved using a two column layout. &nbsp;In vim, I accomplished this through split panes. &nbsp;It is important to see the tests and the code at the same time. &nbsp;</p>


<p>tmux lets me keep a command prompt as a pane in the lower 20% of the screen. &nbsp;This is useful in so many ways. &nbsp;I use it most often for running tests. &nbsp;Using the vim add-on <a href="https://github.com/epeli/slimux">slimux</a>, I can easily send commands to any pane or window I want. &nbsp;Telling that pane to run a test generally requires no more than two keystrokes.</p>


<p>An amazing plugin for Sublime that lets you test is RubyTest. &nbsp;<span>However, tmux allows me to do much more than test. &nbsp;It gives me a full terminal to use that I can expand anytime I want. &nbsp;For example, if I edited a User model to include some database migrations, I would need to run rake db:migrate and rake db:test:prepare before running my actual tests. &nbsp;In Sublime, this requires switching to the terminal app and running those commands, and switching back. &nbsp; In vim, I could accomplish this with :! rake&#8230;.but the resulting output would take up the screen until I pressed enter.</span></p>


<p><span>With tmux, I can do both of these from my text editor without losing focus of my text editor. &nbsp;I am able to see the results of the test and keep typing code.</span></p>


<p>The main advantage of tmux is that I don&#8217;t have to leave tmux for routine editing. &nbsp;Of course, my workflow would be different if I was doing front-end work (designing the site, making sure javascript worked, etc).&nbsp;</p>


<p><strong>Windows</strong></p>


<p>Windows are pretty much just tabs. &nbsp;To my knowledge, tmux doesn&#8217;t really add anything crazy to it, but they are there.&nbsp;</p>


<p><strong>Persistence</strong></p>


<p>tmux has sessions, and it stores persistence. &nbsp;Unless I restart my computer(which does end the session), when I open tmux again, my session will still remain there. &nbsp;Tmux doesn&#8217;t <em>save&nbsp;</em>my session. &nbsp;It keeps running it and by opening tmux again, I am just re-connecting to it.&nbsp;</p>


<p>There are at least two major advantages of this. &nbsp;First, I can quit terminal and come back to my work later without any hesitation. &nbsp;Second, when I return, apps that were running will still be running. &nbsp;I don&#8217;t need to restart my rails server. &nbsp;I don&#8217;t need to open up my rails console again. &nbsp;</p>


<p><strong>Sessions</strong></p>


<p>You can have as many sessions as you want. &nbsp;For me, this means having different projects as different sessions. &nbsp;This allows me to switch between them (or work on both of them) at once really easily. &nbsp;Persistence, as mentioned above, becomes incredibly more useful when dealing with multiple projects.</p>


<p><strong>Negatives</strong></p>


<p>Copy and paste from the Mac clipboard does require an additional program (reattach-to-user-namespace) and work, but it is manageable and worth it.&nbsp;</p>


<p><strong>Plugins worth mentioning</strong></p>


<p><a href="https://github.com/aziz/tmuxinator">Tmuxinator</a> allows you to set defaults and save those projects. &nbsp; Slimux lets you send commands to specific panes. &nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/jgdavey/vim-turbux">Vim-turbux</a> allows you to send testing commands to panes.</p>


<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>


<p>Sorry if any of it came off as confusing; I definitely recommend going through a few of the resources below to get a better understanding of tmux&#8217;s power.</p>


<p>I do love working in tmux, but like vim, there is a slight learning curve before becoming really effective with it. &nbsp;Like vim, the preset defaults aren&#8217;t terrific.</p>


<p>The above reasons are why tmux works well for me. &nbsp;There are a lot of reasons to switch that I haven&#8217;t covered, like working on an <a href="http://bergie.iki.fi/blog/six-weeks-working-android/">android tablet</a> efficiently or using it to <a href="http://pivotallabs.com/how-we-use-tmux-for-remote-pair-programming/">pair program</a>. &nbsp;</p>


<p><strong>Resources</strong></p>


<p>Below are some pretty good resources on experimenting with .tmux and setting it up well. &nbsp;$ indicates a paid resource.</p>


<ul>
<li><span>$&nbsp;<a href="http://pragprog.com/book/bhtmux/tmux">tmux: Productive Mouse Free Development</a> is probably the best guide on tmux there is.&nbsp;</span></li>
<li><span>$ <a href="https://learn.thoughtbot.com/products/4-humans-present-tmux">Thoughtbot - Humans Present Tmux</a></span></li>
<li><a href="http://robots.thoughtbot.com/post/2641409235/a-tmux-crash-course"><span>Thoughtbot - Tmux Crash Course</span></a></li>
<li><span><a href="http://robots.thoughtbot.com/post/19398560514/how-to-copy-and-paste-with-tmux-on-mac-os-x">Thoughtbot - How to Copy and Paste with tmux</a><br /></span></li>
<li><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vHdiXoHKSgU"><span>LA Ruby Conf Talk</span></a></li>
<li><span><a href="http://thechangelog.com/episode-0-7-3-tmux-with-brian-hogan-and-josh-clayton/">The Changelog, Tmux with Brian Hogan and Josh Clayton</a></span></li>
<li>Other people&#8217;s dotfiles. &nbsp;I wouldn&#8217;t recommend <a href="https://github.com/djquan/dotfiles">mine</a>; Josh Clayton is a proficient user and has all <a href="https://github.com/joshuaclayton/dotfiles">his dotfiles up.<br /></a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Backbone, round 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/05/14/backbone-round-1/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-14T12:57:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/05/14/backbone-round-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are a lot of javascript frameworks out there. &nbsp;<a href="http://coding.smashingmagazine.com/2012/07/27/journey-through-the-javascript-mvc-jungle/">This article</a> and <a href="http://todomvc.com/">this site</a> helped to clear up some of my confusion.&nbsp;</p>


<p>I just had my first introduction to these frameworks/libraries with Code School&#8217;s Anatomy of Backbone.js, Part I. &nbsp;<span>Like most of their courses, it was a good </span><strong>introduction</strong><span> to the material that convinced me that I need to learn a lot more about it.</span></p>


<p>PeepCode has released a new screencast on troubleshooting; it was pretty informative. &nbsp;They created a graphic on it <a href="https://peepcode.com/blog/2013/seven-troubleshooting-strategies-poster/img/7strategiesposter.pdf">here</a>. &nbsp;</p>


<p>Mackup, as described in the <a href="http://quan.io/post/50178150864/obligatory-first-pull-request-post-for-those-that">previous post</a>, was featured on <a href="http://lifehacker.com/mackup-backs-up-and-syncs-your-application-settings-acr-504512985">lifehacker</a>!</p>


<p><span>Log for 5/12 - 5/14</span></p>


<ul>
<li>PeepCode - Episode 84, Troubleshooting</li>
<li>A few project euler problems</li>
<li>tmux: Productive Mouse Free Development by Brian Hogan</li>
<li>Started Practical Vim by Drew Neil</li>
<li>CodeSchool - Anatomy of Backbone.js, Part I</li>
</ul>


<p></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pull Request]]></title>
    <link href="http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/05/11/pull-request/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-11T16:03:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/05/11/pull-request</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Obligatory first pull request post! For those that don&#8217;t know, a pull request is a way of contributing back to the open source community. &nbsp;You request that the creator/maintainer&nbsp;of a particular piece of software incorporate your code into the overall code to add a feature or fix a bug. &nbsp;</p>


<p>My first pull request was to <a href="https://github.com/lra/mackup">mackup</a>, a program that lets you keep all your dotfiles (specific configuration files for a variety of apps) in sync through Dropbox. &nbsp;This is an entirely easy thing to do without this software through creating symbolic links, but mackup automates this process, cutting down a lot of time and commands. &nbsp;My contribution was adding support for tmuxinator and teamocil dotfiles. &nbsp;It was only about five lines of additional code, but it still feels good to add features onto a piece of software I use regularly. &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>


<p>Once again, I&#8217;ll recommend Thoughtbot&#8217;s Learn Prime. &nbsp;I&#8217;m currently doing their Test Driven Rails course, and it has been pretty informative so far. &nbsp;It&#8217;s also pretty nice to learn about testing from one of the contributors to FactoryGirl. &nbsp;With learn prime, you get posting privileges to the new <a href="http://forum.thoughtbot.com/">thoughtbot forums</a>. &nbsp;It&#8217;s pretty nice having a a lifeline to the thoughtbot team(including the chat pytel, the ceo, and ben orenstein) on any topic.&nbsp;</p>


<p>If you do any kind of front end text editing, Emmet (formerly zen-coding) is definitely <a href="http://docs.emmet.io/">worth a look.</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>


<p>Log for 5/8 - 5/11</p>


<ul>
<li>Thoughtbot - Test Driven Rails, Writing Integration Tests</li>
<li>Thoughtbot - Humans Present tmux</li>
<li><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vHdiXoHKSgU">Ruby Productivity with Vim and Tmux</a> talk</li>
<li>Started jumpstart labs event-manager tutorial (will try this tutorial entirely in vim)</li>
<li>Ruby Rogues - Episode 104, Book Club discussing The Rails View&nbsp;</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tapas]]></title>
    <link href="http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/05/07/tapas/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-07T16:08:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/05/07/tapas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><p>Ruby Tapas are short screencasts that cover small topics of the Ruby language.   Access to them is $9/month, and the creator (Avdi Grimm) releases three per week.   Go to the site and listen to any number of the free ones he provides and you will realize that it is a great bargain.  I&#8217;m currently working my way through them all and learning a lot. </p>
<p><a href="http://testfirst.org/learn_ruby">Test First Ruby</a> is a pretty interesting way to practice programming.  It&#8217;s a lot like RubyKoans in the sense that it relies on TDD.  There are many chapters with different objects.  For example, one chapter has you create a pig-latin converter.  Another tasks you to create a Reverse Polish Notion calculator.   Some are a lot simpler, like extending the Array class to add a function (of course, whether doing so is a smart idea is another thing). </p>
<p>A goal for the coming week is to check out some front-end resources.  I love playing around and programming in Ruby, but it&#8217;s not the only thing I need to learn well. </p>
<p>Log for 5/2 - 5/7</p>
<ul><li>Ruby Tapas - #1 - 10</li>
<li>Completed Test First Ruby</li>
</ul></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Efficiency]]></title>
    <link href="http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/05/01/efficiency/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-01T16:14:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/05/01/efficiency</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><p><span>A major lesson I&#8217;ve learned from experimenting with vim is that efficiency does matter, no matter the editor.  The tools a person chooses are important, and it&#8217;s important to be efficient and precise with them.  </span></p>
<p>In vimadventures, they have these levels where you have to accomplish certain editing and navigating texts within a certain number of keystrokes. The goal is to make you think about it now, so that it can be engrained later.  </p>
<p>I&#8217;m still up in the air about making it my primary editor, but it has changed the way I approach Sublime Text.  I&#8217;m constantly asking, is there a way I can do <em>x </em>without reaching for the mouse and without pressing too many keys.   To rephrase an earlier statement, the tools a person chooses are important, but it&#8217;s more important to be efficient and precise with them than choosing the perfect one. </p>
<p>This <a href="https://www.hackerschool.com/manual">manual</a> by hacker school is pretty awesome.  The parts on social rules and pair programming are worth a gander.</p>
<p>Toying around with moving the &#8220;Curriculum&#8221; session <a href="https://trello.com/b/NApK9yRl">to a Trello board</a>.  It&#8217;s easier to maintain, allows any trello user to comment, and will help me get used to trello.</p>
<p>Log for 4/30 - 5/1</p>
<ul><li>Started Test-First-Ruby</li>
<li><a href="https://tutsplus.com/course/improve-workflow-in-sublime-text-2/">Tuts+ tutorial</a> on setting up a good ST2 workflow</li>
<li>Spent a lot of time trying to get an efficient workflow&#8230;went back and forth between vim and ST2 a lot.  I&#8217;m working on posting <a href="https://trello.com/board/my-setup/5181b0017dca609775002b0d">my current setup </a>with both on trello.  </li>
</ul></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thoughtbot - Intermediate]]></title>
    <link href="http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/04/29/thoughtbot-intermediate/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-29T16:16:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/04/29/thoughtbot-intermediate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><p><span>I finished Thoughtbot&#8217;s Intermediate Ruby on Rails Workshop.  I, without a doubt, learned a lot from it.  I</span><span>t works out to being $100 with a Learn Prime subscription.   For that price, you get the material (approximately four hours of video), and constant access to the instructor and office hours every week.  I&#8217;d recommend this workshop for this access more than the content (which was quite good too).   I&#8217;m going to be their taking online Test Driven Rails Workshop in May. </span></p>
<p>The Well Grounded Rubyist is an amazing book.  I have a much better understanding of Ruby after reading it.   The first half of the book really prepares you for the second, and it goes from good to amazing in Chapter 10: Enumerables.   It is a long book, but I highly recommend taking a look as it greatly enhanced my comprehension (and love) of Ruby.  </p>
<ul><li><span>Learning more about regular expressions and MatchData has definitely made them less scary(and kind of exciting!).  </span></li>
<li><span>Learning more about the enumerable module gives me a better picture of when to use each method.   Also, knowing that anything can be made to be enumerable-like by adding one method (and an include) is exciting. </span></li>
</ul><p><span>I&#8217;m playing around with zsh (and oh-my-zsh), and I really like it so far.  Tons of great functionality right from installing it.</span></p>
<p>I also started playing around with vim; I&#8217;m not as sure about that, but it&#8217;s getting more appealing the more I learn.  I figure, even if I don&#8217;t end up using it as my full-time text editor (ST2 is so shiny), it&#8217;s still good to have a grasp of it.  Although as I&#8217;m writing this, <a href="http://xkcd.com/1205/">xkcd&#8217;s newest comic</a> asks how long can you work on making a routine task more efficient before you&#8217;re spending more time than you save.</p>
<p>Project Euler gives language agnostic coding challenges requiring you to create code to help you set up a math problem.  For example, find all the sum of the even Fibonacci numbers up to four million.  They&#8217;re great exercises to work through to help improve basic programming.  </p>
<p><a href="http://news.yahoo.com/blogs/this-could-be-big-abc-news/back-school-job-150849131.html?vp=1">A new article (and video) on App Academy.</a></p>
<p>Log for 4/22 - 4/29</p>
<ul><li>Finished Thoughtbot&#8217;s Intermediate Ruby on Rails Workshop</li>
<li>Introduction to Thoughbot&#8217;s Test Driven Rails</li>
<li>Finished Well Grounded Rubyist</li>
<li>vimtutor</li>
<li>PeepCode -  Episode 46, Smash into Vim I</li>
<li>PeepCode -  Episode 47, Smash into Vim II</li>
<li>Thoughtbot - Vim for Rails Developers</li>
<li>Started vimadventures</li>
<li>Started with Project Euler</li>
</ul></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[App Academy]]></title>
    <link href="http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/04/21/app-academy/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-21T11:34:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/04/21/app-academy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been accepted and will attend <a href="http://www.appacademy.io/">App Academy</a> in September. &nbsp;App Academy is a <a href="http://www.wired.com/business/2013/03/free-learn-to-code-boot-camp/">well respected</a>&nbsp;&#8220;bootcamp&#8221; for web development. &nbsp;Having been through a fairly difficult police academy, using the term bootcamp for a programming course is difficult for me&#8230;.but I have no doubt that it will be among the most difficult challenges I have tackled.</p>


<p>I feel really lucky and blessed that I was accepted there. &nbsp;It does seem to be appear one of the hardest programs to get into. &nbsp;My suggestion for those applying to any of the programs is to learn the basics of ruby before applying. This will show that you are passionate about programming, and will help you get through any technical tests. &nbsp; My other suggestion is to not freak out about the technical tests; just talk your way through it. &nbsp;It is okay to make mistakes.</p>


<p>This site has been mainly documenting my journey of learning on my own. I feel that the &#8220;bootcamp&#8221; model that is rapidly expanding is right <em>for me</em> for the following reasons.&nbsp;</p>


<ul>
<li>Accelerating and focusing learning</li>
<li>Gaining experience with the soft skills of development</li>
<li>To gain credibility when applying for junior developer jobs.</li>
</ul>


<p>Furthermore, App Academy in SF seems like the perfect choice for me.</p>


<ul>
<li>Location. &nbsp; San Francisco is the heart of the tech industry, and living and learning in SF will be key to getting an entry level job.</li>
<li>Business model. &nbsp; App Academy collects tuition as a percentage of your first year&#8217;s salary. &nbsp; The majority of&nbsp;tuition&nbsp;is due after, is comparable to other developer bootcamps, and is only due if they succeed in teaching you. &nbsp;This is&nbsp;immensely&nbsp;more&nbsp;affordable&nbsp;than paying $7-12+k before attending the first day.</li>
<li>Business model. &nbsp;App Academy&#8217;s business model shows their commitment to&nbsp;<em>each&nbsp;</em>individual student&#8217;s success.</li>
<li>One cohort at a time. &nbsp;It seems the cycles do not overlap, leading to the focus being your class&#8217; progress as a whole. &nbsp;Dev Bootcamp, on the other hand, often has at least three cohorts running at once.</li>
</ul>


<p><span>This upcoming journey is very exciting, but also pretty terrifying. &nbsp;Not only am I pursuing a different career, but I also will be uprooting myself from my life in DC, where I have lived for over 7 years. &nbsp;&nbsp;</span></p>


<p><span>With that said, this blog will continue to show how I am learning web development on my own until September. &nbsp; Once App Academy begins, it will chronicle my journey there.&nbsp;</span></p>


<p>I&#8217;d like to recommend RubyMonk as a great starting point for learning Ruby. &nbsp;It is a great introduction to the language. &nbsp; In my opinion, it&#8217;s much more effective than codecademy. &nbsp;Moreover, the problems they have are top notch and force you to think.&nbsp;</p>


<p><span>Log for 4/10 - 4/21</span></p>


<ul>
<li>PeepCode - Episode 83, Play by Play with Ben Orenstein</li>
<li>RubyMonk Primer (Complete except a handful of problems)</li>
<li>Thoughtbot&#8217;s Intermediate Ruby on Rails course - Part 3</li>
<li>Agile Development with Heroku webinar</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Older posts..]]></title>
    <link href="http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/04/12/older-posts/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-12T16:17:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/04/12/older-posts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Older posts can be found at <a href="http://dan-quan.tumblr.com">dan-quan.tumblr.com</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
