<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: AppAcademy | Daniel Quan]]></title>
  <link href="http://djquan.github.io/blog/categories/appacademy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://djquan.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-22T15:29:52-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://djquan.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Daniel Quan]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[djquan@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[App Academy]]></title>
    <link href="http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/04/21/app-academy/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-21T11:34:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/04/21/app-academy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been accepted and will attend <a href="http://www.appacademy.io/">App Academy</a> in September. &nbsp;App Academy is a <a href="http://www.wired.com/business/2013/03/free-learn-to-code-boot-camp/">well respected</a>&nbsp;"bootcamp" for web development. &nbsp;Having been through a fairly difficult police academy, using the term bootcamp for a programming course is difficult for me....but I have no doubt that it will be among the most difficult challenges I have tackled.</p>


<p>I feel really lucky and blessed that I was accepted there. &nbsp;It does seem to be appear one of the hardest programs to get into. &nbsp;My suggestion for those applying to any of the programs is to learn the basics of ruby before applying. This will show that you are passionate about programming, and will help you get through any technical tests. &nbsp; My other suggestion is to not freak out about the technical tests; just talk your way through it. &nbsp;It is okay to make mistakes.</p>


<p>This site has been mainly documenting my journey of learning on my own. I feel that the "bootcamp" model that is rapidly expanding is right <em>for me</em> for the following reasons.&nbsp;</p>


<ul>
<li>Accelerating and focusing learning</li>
<li>Gaining experience with the soft skills of development</li>
<li>To gain credibility when applying for junior developer jobs.</li>
</ul>


<p>Furthermore, App Academy in SF seems like the perfect choice for me.</p>


<ul>
<li>Location. &nbsp; San Francisco is the heart of the tech industry, and living and learning in SF will be key to getting an entry level job.</li>
<li>Business model. &nbsp; App Academy collects tuition as a percentage of your first year's salary. &nbsp; The majority of&nbsp;tuition&nbsp;is due after, is comparable to other developer bootcamps, and is only due if they succeed in teaching you. &nbsp;This is&nbsp;immensely&nbsp;more&nbsp;affordable&nbsp;than paying $7-12+k before attending the first day.</li>
<li>Business model. &nbsp;App Academy's business model shows their commitment to&nbsp;<em>each&nbsp;</em>individual student's success.</li>
<li>One cohort at a time. &nbsp;It seems the cycles do not overlap, leading to the focus being your class' progress as a whole. &nbsp;Dev Bootcamp, on the other hand, often has at least three cohorts running at once.</li>
</ul>


<p><span>This upcoming journey is very exciting, but also pretty terrifying. &nbsp;Not only am I pursuing a different career, but I also will be uprooting myself from my life in DC, where I have lived for over 7 years. &nbsp;&nbsp;</span></p>


<p><span>With that said, this blog will continue to show how I am learning web development on my own until September. &nbsp; Once App Academy begins, it will chronicle my journey there.&nbsp;</span></p>


<p>I'd like to recommend RubyMonk as a great starting point for learning Ruby. &nbsp;It is a great introduction to the language. &nbsp; In my opinion, it's much more effective than codecademy. &nbsp;Moreover, the problems they have are top notch and force you to think.&nbsp;</p>


<p><span>Log for 4/10 - 4/21</span></p>


<ul>
<li>PeepCode - Episode 83, Play by Play with Ben Orenstein</li>
<li>RubyMonk Primer (Complete except a handful of problems)</li>
<li>Thoughtbot's Intermediate Ruby on Rails course - Part 3</li>
<li>Agile Development with Heroku webinar</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
