<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Conference | Daniel Quan]]></title>
  <link href="http://djquan.github.io/blog/categories/conference/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://djquan.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-17T19:56:27-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://djquan.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Daniel Quan]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[djquan@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ruby Nation, Day I]]></title>
    <link href="http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/06/14/ruby-nation/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-14T16:53:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://djquan.github.io/blog/2013/06/14/ruby-nation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first day of RubyNation is done, and I thought I&rsquo;d post some things I learned.</p>

<p>Sandi Metz did her talk on the magic tricks of testing; you really should check a <a href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/2452-railsconf2013-the-magic-tricks-of-testing">version</a> of it out.  She, and her book, are amazing for programmers of any level.  This talk is solely on unit testing.  She stresses not over-testing and not repeating test coverage.</p>

<ul>
<li>Test that your objects, when they receive a query or command, respond to them appropriately.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t test private methods.  If you need to, don&rsquo;t get attached to them; delete them when they break.</li>
<li>Test that your object sends a particular command; not exactly the consequences of it as another object will test the side-effects.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t test methods that an object sends to itself. Don&rsquo;t test queries that an object sends to another.</li>
</ul>


<p>Really, check out her talk(and her book!).  It&rsquo;s quite good. I particularly like the analogy of objects as space capsules.</p>

<p>Russ Olsen launched RubyNation with an interesting talk on intuition and those &ldquo;Aha!&rdquo; moments. He talked a little bit about pair programming, including a nice little rule:</p>

<ul>
<li>if your pair and you are stuck, sit in quiet and don&rsquo;t type for two minutes while thinking through the problems.</li>
</ul>


<p>He also discussed another profession that works in pairs in the same manner: police officers. As a former police officer, I could definitely appreciate the comparison. For a lot of my time with the department, I worked directly with a partner.  We were much more effective as a team than independently.</p>

<p>Emily Stolfo had a nice <a href="http://www.confreaks.com/videos/2493-railsconf2013-hacking-the-academic-experience">talk</a> on hacking the academic experience where she listed five traits she tries to teach students:</p>

<ul>
<li>Use the internet as a textbook</li>
<li>Able to debug code you didn&rsquo;t write</li>
<li>Build something to solve a real-life problem</li>
<li>Engage with the community</li>
<li>Think critically about code</li>
</ul>


<p>There were a few other memorable talks. Bryan Helmkamp spoke about security in rails applications.  He recommends the <a href="http://brakemanscanner.org/">Brakeman gem</a> for checking vulnerabilities.  It reviews your code for common (but not all) vulnerabilities.</p>

<p>Two people spoke about doing DevOps on President Obama&rsquo;s re-election campaign. Learning about the technologies that went into the campaign was interesting.  It was more from the perspective of a system administrator than a developer, but I still found it helpful in understanding how sites scale.  I&rsquo;ve been focusing on code for the past four months, and it&rsquo;s easy to forget that code is run on machines.  Heroku is fine for playing around with and learning (and it&rsquo;s fine for production environments too), but there are other options and technical considerations when developing a site/application that will actually receive heavy traffic.</p>

<p>I learned a lot, and day two should be just as great. Some final thoughts</p>

<ul>
<li>Don&rsquo;t be afraid to say you&rsquo;re a complete beginner.  Most people are friendly and want to help.</li>
<li>There are a lot of freelancers out there making a living off contracts ~ Most said that it was really easy to get contracts.</li>
<li>Be friendly and introduce yourself to people.</li>
<li>I&rsquo;m doing better with imposter syndrome.  It&rsquo;s easy to think you don&rsquo;t have the skills to belong at the table, but everyone is learning something.  Some people happen to be learning more.</li>
<li>It wouldn&rsquo;t be the worst idea to take handwritten notes.</li>
</ul>


<p>Random unrelated vim tip:</p>

<p><code>vim Press ctrl-l after a search is complete to turn off highlighting. From Practical Vim.
nnoremap &lt;silent&gt; &lt;C-l&gt; :&lt;C-u&gt;nohlsearch&lt;CR&gt;&lt;C-l&gt;
</code></p>

<p><img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/6565481/rubynation.jpg" alt="RubyNation" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
